Carson B.

Email: ******** blocked out to prevent craigslist spam, this resume is from a craigslist ad, contact for more info mobile: via email

Objective

Looking for an Android oriented Engineering position, full-time and remote. I have ~10+ years of experience developing Android applications from scratch at home/small/medium/large size companies. Experience and expertise in many areas such as IoT, Location-Services, E-Commerce, Camera APIs(2dir, ocr), refactoring, kotlin, compose, etc.

Professional Experience

Walmart Global Tech 08/2022 - 12/2022

Software Engineer III

 Worked on an undocumented module developed by contracted foreign engineers whose first language was not english and assisted them in integrating their code for a simple feature into WalMart's monolithic module-oriented test-driven repository.

SeaWorld Parks & Entertainment

12/2021 - 04/2022

Senior Android Engineer

- Worked with outsourced team to transition codebase and ci/cd process to microsoft ado services
- Implemented/worked on minor features, improvements, and bug fixes throughout the application
- Kotlin, MVI, ViewModel, jetpack libraries, androidx, mapbox sdk, analytics sdks, etc

Lucid Motors

08/10/2020 - 08/16/2021, Newark, CA

Software Engineer (Android)

- Coded the 1st proper Kotlin/MVVM app the entire company has ever seen. This app was an R&D project for
 future product(car) releases. Android AOSP has a hard time running Kotlin applications so they wanted to
 get access to well-written code to figure out the proper way to run Kotlin/Java apps side-by-side on their
 Android Framework. I witnessed, in GitLab, many engineers converting my Kotlin project into Java code and
 taking code snippets of that into their own company projects.
- Worked with a newly formed, contracted... out-sourced... Localization/Internationalization team. Wrote
 confluence guides/docs about Android workflow and git-procedures for future team new-hires, as the
 company scales to diff langs/regions they planned on hiring many cheap low-end contractors to do
 localization changes all over. My guides helped and will help future engineers work efficiently and correctly.
- Fixed a large UI design flaw in a view(HVAC app, controls fan/temp) that visibly upset and disturbed the CEO, and VP of Design, for many months at a time. I knew the solution literally immediately, because I had done it years ago. I pushed an update to our UI Toolkit in 4+ days.

Molekule, Inc

09/2019 - 12/2019, San Francisco, CA

Senior Android Developer

- AWS Cognito, AWS IoT Core, Bluetooth and CoAP communication
- Kotlin, Retrofit, RxJava, Databinding, MVVM, LiveData, Coroutines/Jobs, Jetpack-stuff/etc
- Advised and worked with poorly performing(year over year) outsourced mobile/cloud teams that were given
 full autonomy over all software development practices. Improved team's productivity and efficiency when
 working on projects/features. Advised the teams on MVVM design, Android UI/UX design, professional

- code-reviews with discussions, efficient git procedures, industry standard branch management, why code comments are needed... idiomatic code practices, etc...
- Assigned by COO on day one of the job to physically meet with remote mobile/cloud teams out of country to
 discuss and fix the company's years long problem with IoT connectivity.

Plushcare

01/2019 - 05/2019, San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer (Android)

- Agile environment, daily stand-up, coordinated with mobile engineering team and product daily
- Began Kotlin app rework. (company moved towards react-native)
- Android/3rd Party Libraries: Glide/Stripe/Volley/OAuth/etc
- Focused on product quality, material design, ui/ux. Svg assets, object animators, advocated for simple Androidy design during meetings and/or brand designs when applicable(ie: native or custom progressbar)
- Fixed bugs and crashes in legacy Java application when needed, with fixes pushed to staging(github) same day. Also implemented smaller, simpler features. ie: via WebViews

Shopkick

03/2018 - 12/2018

Software Engineer (Android)

- Implemented/worked on features all throughout the app including features that use 3rd party libraries for things such as 2d-image-recognition and optical-character-recognition(OCR).
- Updated and reworked lots of UI/UX within the application to be more up to date with fast moving Design-Guidelines such as Google's Material Design. (ie: SVG path-morphing)
- Participated in daily feature oriented stand-ups, attended bi-weekly guild meetings, worked with off-shore devs to ensure high code quality.
- Obsessed over Android product quality and interfaced with product team almost daily to jog/bounce improvements, ideas, and UI/UX.

SiC Studios

12/2016 - 03/2018

Android Engineer

- Developed the alpha version of a FinTech investment training app under the umbrella of SiC Studios called TestInvest.
- The focus of Alpha and/or the foundation of the application is a unique stock market simulator that enables users to learn to make smart investment decisions via trades on their portfolios/games.
- Native Android development: Java, Android SDK, Android Support Libraries
- 3rd Party Libraries/etc: Firebase, Retrofit, Picasso, MPAndroidCharts, gson, etc..

The Cube

04/2016 - 12/2016

Android Engineer

- The Cube is a service that allows you to record/stream your favorite moments and events(ie: middle/high school sports!) for your friends and family
- Maintained The Cube's Android application; Java, Android SDK/Support Libs, Picasso, Ion, Crashlytics, etc...
- Worked directly with backend, ios, design team, QA team. Agile environment
- Moved application forward and towards Material Design -- RecyclerView > ListView -- custom 'chips' Pull to refresh , tablet/ui fragmentation support

Android Dev Intern

Learned Github/Git -- Got immersed into an agile development process -- Scrum meetings everyday -- First
Software Engineering job -- Worked directly with a Senior Android Engineer and Senior Web Engineer on a
daily basis as well as a Junior QA employee and another Software Engineering Intern.

Skillset

- Strong skills in Android SDK Dev, Kotlin, Java, XML, Android Studio, ANDROID COMPOSE
- Strong understanding of Android device fragmentation, localization, material design, Android UI/UX
- Strong eye for quality of product relative to the Android platform
- Strong experience with source control and bug tracking tools (GIT, Gitlab, Github, Bitbucket, etc..)
- Strong understanding of OOP
- Experience with a plethora of 3rd Party Libraries and techniques, and other Android plug-ins such as Firebase and Fabric/Crashlytics, image-recognition integration, optical character recognition(ocr)
- Great understanding of REST/JSON/asynchronous requests for data, Retrofit/Glide
- Creative approach to problem solving, eagerness to learn and understand

Android Projects

• GEO Alarm - (ongoing) - A simple app that notifies you when you have entered a geo-fence. Uploading to the play store early this year(2023).

(https://github.com/YoloSwagBot/GeoAlarm)

- TestInvest (ongoing) paper options simulator, android compose, custom chart/graph drawing, etc studying gcloud and how to setup websockets via cli for this project
- Hyena (postponed/ongoing) An app that compiles funny and entertaining content.
- Dev Opts (05/01/19 done, I should probably update it though) A simple settings shortcut app for developers that takes advantage of the "Display over other apps" permission. When setup, the widget sits above other apps' UI, links you to Developer Settings when clicked, and holds a list of favorite settings for ease of use. (https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.appstr.devopts)
- SmartPark (08/14 12/14) A side project with two colleagues. Sensors were created to be put in individual parking spaces that would connect to campus wifi and send occupancy information to a server. This was done using a database and a continuous json feed. I created a prototype android application.
- Music Apps (05/12 09/12) Released over 120+ music oriented(mixtapes) Android apps in 2012 in an attempt to fill a niche in the music industry. They were simple ugly applications that gave the user what they wanted, music media files. 50k+ downloads overall. They are no longer on the Google Play Store.

Education - 4.5 years of Computer Science Study

• Midwestern State University - Computer Science major

Achievements

- ★ Team Lead for the Android App at MSU(2012-2014). I helped start and lead the Android team.
- ★ IdeaMSU 2nd Place (\$1000). An entrepreneurial idea contest at Midwestern State University. My idea was a website to automatically create mobile applications for musicians that uploads them to the Play/iOS store so they can tell people to download their app at concerts and market themselves. Possibly even allowing them to sell their music for a profit.

Technical Interests

 Model-driven UI/UX design – SVG/Path-Morphing/Vector-Graphics and advanced animations, signal theory, IoT comm layers, Artificial Intelligence, Electronic Trading, blockchain, crypto, mass application management, UI/UX/creative automation, functional programing, game theory, gamification, perspective parallelism, entity-bound linguistic modeling, cognition and perception, Perceptual Control Theory, Cybernetics.